Guide to the Muriel Draper Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1905-52; Series I; 4; (10 boxes)
  - Sanders, John B., 1920-28, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 277)
  - Sanders, Nathaniel and May, 1905-46, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 278-81)
  - Sanders, Richard, 1905-11, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 282-85)
  - Sanders, Mrs. Richard, 1905, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 286-89)
  - [Sanders, Mr. and Mrs. Richard] (Box 9, Folder 290)
  - Schnabel, Arthur, 1933, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 291)
  - Scott, Geoffrey, 1928, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 292-93)
  - Seldes, Gilbert and Amanda, 1922-49, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 294)
  - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, 1930, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 295)
  - Stein, Gertrude, 1928, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 296)
  - Stella, Joseph, 1922, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 297)
  - Strachey, John, 1932-40, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 298)
  - Sullivan, Noël, 1931-43 (Box 9, Folder 299)
  - "T" general, 1915-31, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 300)
  - Temple, Richmond, 1923-25 (Box 9, Folder 301)
  - Theis, Otto, 1922 Jul 18 (Box 9, Folder 302)
  - Thomson, Virgil, [ca. 1932] (Box 9, Folder 302a)
  - Tobey, Dorothy Earle, 1923-24, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 303)
  - Tobey, Mark, 1916-30, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 304-11)
  - Tobey, Mark, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 312)
    See also: Box 22, folder 716, and Oversize, Box 26, folder 843
  - Toomer, Jean, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 313)
  - Tryfillis, D., n.d.
  - "U" general, 1918-25, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 313a)
  - "V" general, 1921-41, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 314)
  - V[?], Emily D., 1926-28, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 315)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1922-46, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 316-17)
  - Van Vechten, Carl and Fania, 1927-39, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 318)
  - "W" general, 1916-47, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 319-20)
  - Walsh, Edward DeWitt, 1921-23, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 321)
  - Walsh, Robin
  - Warburg, Edward M. M., 1934 Dec 15, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 322)
  - Waterman, Edward, 1923-33, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 323)
  - Watson, James Sibley, 1926-28, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 324)
  - Watson, Peter Grant, 1915, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 325)
  - Wells, H. G., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 326)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1935, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 327)
  - Whitall, James, 1929-34, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 328-29)
  - Wild, Rudy, 1943-44, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 330)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1930-42, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 331)
  - Wilson, Edmund ("Bunny"), 1929-38, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 332)
  - Wise, E. F., 1931 Oct-Dec (Box 10, Folder 333)
  - Wolfe, Humbert, 1922-24, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 334)
  - Wrynn, Anthony, 1932-43, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 335)
  - "Y" general, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 336)
  - Yale University Library, 1951-52 (Box 10, Folder 337)
  - Yorck, Ruth, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 338)
  - Young, Art, 1942, 1944
  - Zigrosser, Carl, 1942
  - Unidentified, 1911-47, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 339-42)
  - Draper general, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 343-46)
  - Third party correspondence, 1905-52, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 347)
- Writings, 1921-45; Series II; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Boxes 11-14 hold Series II, Writings, which is divided into four sections, Articles, Books, Broadcast Scripts, and Short Stories. Individual works are filed alphabetically within each section.
  - ARTICLES
    - "American Audiences," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 348)
    - "Art," typescripts carbon and corrected (Box 11, Folder 349-51)
    - "As They Listen," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 352)
    - Born to Be Introduction: manuscript and related material (Box 11, Folder 353-54)
    - "Buffetings in a South Wind, Some Memories of Norman Douglas," manuscript (incomplete), typescript, and printed copy (Box 11, Folder 355)
    - "Citizen Welles," typescript and biographical sketch (Box 11, Folder 356)
    - "Conversation in a Moscow Hotel," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 357)
    - "The Devil is Bored," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 358)
    - "Diversions of Democracy," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 359)
    - "The Emotions of Men," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 360)
    - "Five Days in Moscow," manuscript and galleys, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 361)
    - "Furnishing with Adornment," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 362)
    - "He Wants to Know: A. R. Orage," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 363)
    - "I Fly," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 364)
    - "Interesting People are Curious People," printed copy, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 365)
    - "Lew Oldstrom Says," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 366)
    - "London To-Day," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 367)
    - "Madame X," typescripts, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 368)
    - "Makers of Music," printed copy, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 369)
    - "Mary Garden in Her Body," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 370)
    - "Moscow Conversations," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 371)
    - "Moscow Fashions," typescript, [1935] (Box 11, Folder 372)
    - "Moscow Notes," printed versions, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 373)
    - "Moscow Notes," (2 articles), typescripts, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 374)
    - "Music Chronicle, Lieder: Wozzeck," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 375)
    - [Music Education in the USSR], typescript, [1935?] (Box 11, Folder 376)
    - "My Foreign Loan Breakfast," manuscript and typescripts (Box 11, Folder 377)
    - "Opera Next Year (By Which I Mean Mary Garden," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 378)
    - "Prelude to Departure," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 379)
    - "Review of 'A Woman of Paris,'" typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 380)
    - "Review of The Peril of Fascism by A. B. Magil and Henry Stevens," printed copies, 1938 Jul (Box 11, Folder 381)
    - "Robert Locher, His Art and Craft," manuscript, typescript, and notes (Box 11, Folder 382)
    - "Salud," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 383)
    - "The School of the American Ballet," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 384)
    - "A Spasm of Lucidity," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 385)
    - "A Story-Teller's Holiday (with Apologies to George Moore)," manuscript and typescripts (Box 11, Folder 386)
    - "Ten Cents," manuscript and typescript (Box 11, Folder 387)
    - "A Visit to the USSR State Bank," typescripts, [1935] (Box 11, Folder 388)
    - ["We are the sum of what we eat"], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 389)
    - "Wings of an Ostrich," typescript and carbon (Box 11, Folder 390)
    - "Winter Solstice," typescript and printed versions Harper's Bazaar, 1938 Dec (Box 11, Folder 391-92)
    - "Women's Causes and Effects," printed copy Vogue, 1929 Jun 22 (Box 11, Folder 393)
    - Unidentified manuscripts, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 394)
    - Unidentified typescripts, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 395)
    - Fan mail, 1921-32, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 396-97)
  - BOOKS
    - America Deserta
      - Typescript and manuscript (Box 12, Folder 398-420)
      - Typescript, original, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 421-24)
      - Typescript, original, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 425-27)
      - Typescript II, original, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 428-35)
      - Typescript II, carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 436-41)
      - Review, 1933 May 8 (Box 13, Folder 442)
    - Music at Midnight
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 443)
      - Section 1: "A Jewel Lost and Found," manuscript and typescript (Box 13, Folder 444)
      - Section 2: "London - Holland Street," manuscript and typescript (Box 13, Folder 445)
      - Section 3: "I Meet Henry James," manuscript and typescript (Box 13, Folder 446-47)
      - Sections 3 and 4: "London - 19 and 19a Edith Grove," manuscript and typescript, incomplete (Box 13, Folder 448)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 449-52)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 453-54)
      - Proofs, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 455)
      - Fan mail, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 456-58)
      - Film treatment, [1941?] (Box 14, Folder 459)
  - BROADCASTS
    - It's A Woman's World
      - First--scripts and clippings, 1937 Jun (Box 14, Folder 460-61)
      - Second--scripts and clippings, 1937 Jun 15 (Box 14, Folder 462)
      - Third--scripts and clippings, 1937 Jun 22 (Box 14, Folder 463)
      - Fourth--script, 1937 Jun 29 (Box 14, Folder 464)
      - "Democracy in the United States", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 465)
      - "East Meets West in the Dance", 1937 Dec 16 (Box 14, Folder 466)
      - "Interview with Lotte Lehman", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 467)
      - "Minimum Wages Law", 1937 Oct 25 (Box 14, Folder 468)
      - "Muriel Draper and Mother Bloor", 1938 Feb 24, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 469-70)
      - Oberlin College script, 1937 Oct 12 (Box 14, Folder 471)
      - WMCA for Benefit of Spanish Milk Fund, [1937?] Jun 28 (Box 14, Folder 472)
      - Unidentified script, 1937 Nov 1 (Box 14, Folder 473)
      - Fan Mail, 1937, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 474)
      - Related material, 1937, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 475-76)
  - SHORT STORIES
    - "Christmas Day - 1914," manuscript and typescripts (Box 14, Folder 477)
    - "Cox - Mr. Cox - Mr. Leonard E. L. Cox of Station W. A. B. C."
      - Annotated manuscript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 478)
      - Typescript, original and carbon (Box 14, Folder 479)
    - "An Impression," typescript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 480)
    - "Miss Daritt from Detroit" ["Eating and Having Cake"]
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 481)
      - Typescript II, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 482)
      - Typescript III, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 483)
    - "Sightless Eyes"
      - Annotated manuscript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 484)
      - Typescript, incomplete, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 485)
    - Untitled manuscript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 486)
    - Untitled typescript, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 487)
- Personal Papers, 1881-1977; Series III; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is housed in Boxes 15-17 and is arranged alphabetically by type of material. Information on members of the Draper family other than Muriel Draper is located under the names of the individuals.
  - Address book, 1906 (Box 15, Folder 488)
  - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 489)
  - Art and architecture: articles and photographs (Box 15, Folder 490)
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 491-93)
    See also: Oversize, Box 26, folders 844-46
  - Baptismal certificate, 1922 Jun 1 (Box 15, Folder 494)
  - Biographical information, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 495)
  - Clippings, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 496)
  - Diary pages, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 497)
  - Draper, Paul
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 498)
    - Newspaper clippings: divorce announcement and reviews (Box 15, Folder 499)
    - Obituaries, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 500)
  - Draper, Paul Jr.
    - Application to the Groton School, 1922, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 501)
    - Artwork, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 502)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1929-51, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 503-04)
  - Draper, Raimond Sanders
    - Correspondence, 1933 Dec 25 (Box 15, Folder 505)
    - Death certificate, 1943
    - Hair, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 506)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d.
  - Draper, Ruth
    - Obituary, 1956 Dec 31 (Box 15, Folder 507)
  - Financial notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 508)
  - Greeting cards, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 509)
    See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 847
  - Guest lists, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 510)
  - Hats
    Includes hat worn in Muriel Draper's obituary photo.
  - Interior Decoration
    - Administrative information, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 511)
    - Floor plans, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 512-13)
    - Miscellaneous lists, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 514)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 515)
    - Sketches
      - Completed sketches, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 516-18)
      - Rough sketches, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 519-21)
      - Rough sketches, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 522-23)
      - Sketch by Paul Chalfin, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 524)
    - Writings, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 525-26)
  - Invitations, 1881-1952, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 527)
  - Lecture Tours
    - Contracts and itineraries, 1930-31 (Box 16, Folder 528)
    - Lectures
      - "Charm", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 529)
      - "We All Wear Clothes", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 530)
      - Untitled [?], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 531)
    - Notices, 1929-30 (Box 16, Folder 532)
  - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 533)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1907-77, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 534)
  - North Boca Raton Company: correspondence, receipts, and shares, 1925-27 (Box 16, Folder 535)
  - Notes, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 536-37)
  - Obituary, 1952 Aug 26 (Box 16, Folder 538)
  - Photographs
    People
    - Alington, Lord Napier
    - See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 848
    - Anderson, Sherwood [?] (Box 16, Folder 539)
    - Arthur, Esther Murphy Strachey, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 540)
    - Brown, Harris, 1931 Dec (Box 16, Folder 541)
    - Douglas, Norman, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 849
    - Draper, Muriel, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 850
    - Draper, Paul (photograph by Emelie Danielson) See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 851
    - Ewing, Max, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 544)
    - Garden, Mary, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 545)
    - See also: Oversize, Box 26, folders 852-53
    - Gordon, Taylor, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 546)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - Larsson, Raymond E. F. (Box 16, Folder 548)
    - Lowenfels, Walter, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 549)
    - [Murphy, Esther], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 549a)
    - Ogden, C. K., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 550)
    - Rothermere, Lady Lillian, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 551)
    - Rubinstein, Arthur, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 552)
    - Tobey, Mark, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 553)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 554)
    - Groups, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 555)
    - Objects
      - Busts and statues (Box 17, Folder 556)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 854
      - Chairs, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 557)
      - Houses, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 558)
      - See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 855
      - Paintings, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 559)
      - Still-lifes, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 560)
      - Window display See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 856
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 561-63)
      See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 857-58
  - Printed material
    - Elizabeth Duncan School, [1925?] (Box 17, Folder 564)
    - Exhibitions, 1927, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 565)
    - Programs, 1927, 1938, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 566)
  - Sanders family, 1927, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 567)
  - Sanders, Thomas: schoolwork and obituary (Box 17, Folder 568)
  - Sheet music: "Sacred Hour of Love", 1929 (Box 17, Folder 569)
  - Travel papers
    - Spain, 1937, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 570)
    - USSR, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 571)
  - Valentines, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 572)
- Subject Files, 1921-1976; Series IV; 3.25; (8 boxes)
  Boxes 18-25 hold Series IV, Subject Files. The series is composed of two sections, People and Organizations and Causes. Material within each section has been alphabetically arranged, first by subject and then by type of material.
  - PEOPLE
    - Anderson, Garland: pamphlet and reviews, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 573)
    - Antheil, George: advertisement, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 574)
    - Arthur, Esther Murphy Strachey
      - Book reviews, 1922-24, [1937] (Box 18, Folder 575)
      - Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 576)
      - Political fliers, 1929, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 577)
    - Bloor, Ella Reeve: anniversary banquet program, 1947 Jun 20 (Box 18, Folder 578)
    - Chalfin, Paul: obituary, 1959 Feb 16 (Box 18, Folder 579)
    - Corley, Donald
      - Annotated advertisements, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 580)
      - Artwork
        See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 859
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 581)
      - Obituary, 1955 Dec 14
      - "The Silver Spoon of El-Charad", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 582)
    - Courtauld, Samuel
      - Financial correspondence, 1925 May-Sep (Box 18, Folder 583)
      - Letters to the Editor, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 584)
    - Cummings, Edward Estlin
      - Eimi, dust jacket, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 585)
      - Him, galleys and clippings, 1926-[27?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 586-87)
      - Printed poetry, 1935 Mar 7 (Box 18, Folder 588)
    - Douglas, Norman, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 589)
    - Field, Stanley: clippings, 1921, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 590)
    - Garden, Mary: Society of Arts and Sciences correpondence, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 591)
    - Gurdjieff, Georges
      Beelzebub's Tales
      - Typescript I, Chapters I-XXIII, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 592-600)
      - Typescript I, Chapters XXIV-XXX, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 601-06)
      - Typescript II, Chapters I-XLVII, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 607-21)
      - Lecture number one, [1924 Jan] (Box 19, Folder 622)
      - "The First Chapter of the Third Series," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 623-24)
      - Institute for the Harmonious Development of Man
        - Announcements, 1930-33, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 625)
        - Correspondence, 1924-44, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 626)
        - Epigraph and "Inner Freedom Towards Life," typescript, carbon, 1930 (Box 20, Folder 627)
        - Lecture notes, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 628-29)
        - Notes by Muriel Draper, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 630-34)
        - Membership information, 1924, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 635)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1924, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 636)
        - New York Group of A. R. Orage, 1934, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 637-40)
        - Pamphlets, 1943-44, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 641)
    - Hartmann, Thomas de: biographical sketch and reviews (Box 20, Folder 642)
    - Hitchcock, Henry Russell: "American Architecture", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 643)
    - J. K.: poetry, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 644)
    - Jones, Ruth Lambert: poetry, 1922-29, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 645)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln
      - Advertisements, 1934-48, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 646)
      - Articles, 1938-45, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 647)
      - Correspondence, 1931-52, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 648-49)
      - Miscellaneous, 1930-33, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 650)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1935-47, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 651)
      - Personal papers, 1941-42 (Box 20, Folder 652)
      - "Post-cards," typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 653-54)
      - Programs, 1935-47, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 655-56)
      - Reviews, 1935, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 657)
      - Untitled poetry, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 658)
    - Larsson, Raymond E. F.
      - Artwork, 1939-49, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 659-61)
      - Correspondence, 1938, 1947, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 662)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1925, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 663)
      - Poetry: manuscripts, 1938, 1962, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 664)
      - Poetry: typescripts, 1925-52, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 665-66)
      - Poetry: galleys and printed versions (Box 21, Folder 667)
      - Writings, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 668)
      - Writings of others, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 669)
    - Lasell, Philip: artwork, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 670)
    - Lowenfels, Walter
      - Articles and clippings, 1924-25, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 671)
      - "An Elegy for D. H. Lawrence," printer's copy, advertisements, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 672)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 673)
      - Poetry, typescripts, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 674-78)
      - Short story and plays, typescripts (Box 21, Folder 679)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge
      - Articles and clippings, 1932, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 680)
      - European Experiences, Chapter 10 ("Muriel"), galleys, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 681)
    - MacLeish, Archibald: fragments from Panic, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 682)
    - McMullin, John
      - "American Chic," typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 683)
      - "The Vogue of the Dinner Coat," manuscript and typescript, 1920 Mar 4
    - Nesbitt, P.: artwork, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 684)
    - Ogden, C. K.
      - Books and Authors: page proof (incomplete) (Box 21, Folder 685)
      - Basic English: printed material, 1929, 1941, n.d.
      - Miscellaneous, 1927-31, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 686)
    - Patten, William H.
      - "Music at Midday", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 687)
      - Decorator's sketch, n.d.
    - Putnam, H. Phelps: "Romeo and Juliet," typescript (Box 21, Folder 688)
    - Rigaut, Jaques
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 689)
      - Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 690)
      - Printed material, 1931, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 691)
    - Rodgers, [?]: "Asp of the Age," galleys, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 692)
    - Ross, Cary
      - Miscellaneous, 1931-35, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 693)
      - "Moscow Letter," typescript, carbon, 1935 May (Box 22, Folder 694)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1933-35, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 695)
      - Poetry, 1934, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 696)
    - Rothermere, Lady Lillian
      - Advertisements, 1922, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 697)
      - Correspondence, 1926 May 10
    - Scott, Geoffrey: obituaries, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 698)
    - Seldes, Gilbert: newspaper clippings and posters (Box 22, Folder 699)
    - Seldes, Marian and Tim: greeting cards (Box 22, Folder 700)
    - Sitwell, Edith: newspaper clipping, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 701)
    - Sitwell, Osbert
      - At the House of Mrs. Kinfoot, 1921 (Box 22, Folder 702)
      - "Great Morning" (excerpt), typescript, n.d.
      - "Rat Week", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 703)
      - Who Killed Cock Robin?, 1921
    - Sitwell, Sacheverell: article and notes on, 1929-44 (Box 22, Folder 704)
    - Stein, Gertrude
      - Advertisement, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 705)
      - "Pictures": press release, n.d.
    - Strachey, John (Box 22, Folder 706)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1935, n.d.
      - Political flier, n.d.
    - Syzmanowski, Karol
      - Correspondence, 1922 Jan 30 (Box 22, Folder 707)
      - "Le roi roger," operatic libretto, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 708-09)
    - Tobey, Mark
      Artwork
      - Ink drawings, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 710-1)
      - Pencil sketches, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 712-14)
      - See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 860
      - Autobiographical sketch, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 715)
      - Business correpondence, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 716)
      - Exhibition program, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 717)
      - Newspaper clipping, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 718)
      - Obituary, 1976
    - Toomer, Jean: Essentials advertisement, [1930?] (Box 22, Folder 719)
    - Watson, E. L. Grant: "In the Studio," typescript, [1928?] (Box 22, Folder 720)
    - Wells, W. H., 1931 (Box 22, Folder 721)
    - Wheelwright, John Brooks: "And for his mother," manuscript, 1926 (Box 22, Folder 722)
    - White, Kenneth: "Memorandum to a Lover," typescript (Box 22, Folder 723)
    - Williams, Howard: "Tales of a Talker," typescript, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 724)
    - Wilson, Edmund
      - Articles, 1926-38 (Box 22, Folder 725)
      - "Karl Marx: a Prolet-Play,", n.d.
      - Travels, galleys, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 726-28)
    - Wolfe, Humbert: poetry, manuscripts, typescripts, and printed versions (Box 22, Folder 729-30)
    - Wolfe, W. Béran: pamphlets, 1932 Mar-Apr (Box 22, Folder 731)
  - ORGANIZATIONS AND CAUSES
    - Actor's Thrift Shop, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 732)
    - American Commedia dell' Arte
      - Account statements, [n.y. Mar-Oct] (Box 23, Folder 733)
      - Article on painting [by Vadim Uraneff?], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 734)
      - Bank book, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 735)
      - Bills and expenses, 1921-22 (Box 23, Folder 736)
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1922 Jun 2 (Box 23, Folder 737)
      - Correspondence, 1920-26, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 738-42)
      - Membership lists, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 743)
      - Minutes, by-laws, and lease, 1922
      - Newspaper clippings, 1922, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 744)
      - Notes [by Muriel Draper], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 745)
      - Printed material, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 746)
      - Programs, n.d.
      - Receipts, 1921, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 747)
      - "The Second Vision," typescript (Box 23, Folder 748)
      - Shares, 1922 Jun 26 (Box 23, Folder 749)
      - Statements of purpose, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 750)
      - Tax forms, 1922-25 (Box 23, Folder 751-52)
    - American Committee for Anti-Nazi Seamen, 1938 Sep 30 (Box 23, Folder 753)
    - American Committee for Spanish Relief, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 754)